

CONTACT

- stevengraham0214@gmail.com
- github.com/mastercodercat
- 🕥 twitter.com/@graham_steven
- @smartXmaster

SKILL

Java

Ruby on Rails

JavaScript/TypeScript

React/Next/Svelte/Ember

Vue/Nuxt

Angular

Python/Flask/Django

PHP/Laravel/Symfony

Shopify/WordPress/Magento

Node/Nest

STEVEN GRAHAM

SENIOR FULL-STACK ENGINEER

ABOUT ME

Senior Software Developer with 7+ Years of Experience.

Experienced with numerous software technologies focusing on web and blockchain development.

Got prize in ACM which is part of ICPC when I was a college student. Led development of \$150K research project which was deemed a "silver standard" by the client. Increased client's revenue 2-fold after fine-tuning AI/ML-based algorithms.

Provide high-quality code and power communication.

Eager to support building an impeccable online reputation by providing high-level customer support for start-ups and firms.

Worked on flexible projects for unlimited clients around the world. Strong at building architecture of backend systems and have good sensitive

in frontend developing.

Specialist at Test Driven Development.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR FULL-STACK ENGINEER

July 2022 - Present The Crypto Company, United State, Remote

- Strategic and management consulting for blockchain and cryptocurrency, from ICOs to capital raises to systems design.
- Backend development using Python/Django integrated Unit testing for backend system and used to deploy server to digital ocean using Docker.
- Integrated Django CMS using wagtail to build page more easily and more fantastic.
- Built and launched Smart Contracts for Genesis NFT, Pod and Marketplace as well. Prefer to use ERC-721 based NFT rather than ERC-1155.
- Supported the DevOps team to automate CI/CD processes.
- Worked with Core Java to develop automated solutions to include web interfaces using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Web services.
- Implemented complex UI components with React / Vue / TypeScript and SCSS.
- Developed pages routing capabilities for bookmarking, filters, validations and React components such as grid, buttons, carousels, date pickers, modal dialogs and other input component.

SENIOR FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Feb 2018 - June 2022 Emtec, United State, Remote

- Led seven members of web development team. Managed project using github and manage team members with ticket using Clickup.
- Utilize Python/Django, PostgreSQL to implement scalable Full Stack Software solutions.

SQL/NoSQL Web3 Golang Rust Solidity CI/CD **AWS** Docker LANGUANGE English **Finnish**

COURSE

- Solidity Smart Contracts:
 Build DApps in Ethereum Blockchain
 Get Certificate, Udemy
 July 2018 Aug 2019
- Ethereum and Solidity: The Developer's complete guide, Udemy Feb 2018 – June 2018

HOBBIES

- Boxing/Judo/Karate
- Football/Basketball
- · Climbing/Skiing
- · Singing/Dancing

- Participate in the full lifecycle of development for company web application using Django.
- Integrated AuthO login and SendGrid API to send mail to users.
- Created restful APIs using Laravel and consumed them with React.js.
- Configured Google analytics module for tracking the visitors for the website.
- Strong programming experience in Laravel with sufficient exposure to Windows and Linux.
- Fixed bugs and implemented TDD for both Frontend and Backend.
- Developed Responsive Websites that could be served by desktop, Tablets and mobile devices using React.js.
- Integrated payment system for product checkout using Authorize, payment API.
- Worked with JEST unit test framework to write unit tests for JavaScript code.
- Worked closely with the back-end team to display data using the Custom Components, library components, Redux, Redux-Saga.
- Worked with backend engineers to optimize existing API calls to create efficiencies by deprecating unneeded API calls.

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Nov 2015 - Feb 2018 QVIK, Finland, Hybrid

- Developed an E-commerce platform using React for frontend and NodeJS for backend.
- Developed Responsive Websites that could be served by desktop,
 Tablets and mobile devices using React.js.
- Integrated payment system for product checkout using Authorize, payment API.
- Worked with JEST unit test framework to write unit tests for JavaScript code.
- Worked closely with the back-end team to display data using the Custom Components, library components, Redux, Redux-Saga.
- Worked with backend engineers to optimize existing API calls to create efficiencies by deprecating unneeded API calls.
- Involved in all agile ceremonies like Daily stand-ups, Backlog pointing sessions, Planning sessions, retrospection, etc.
- Implemented various screens for the frontend using React.js and used various predefined components from NPM(Node Package Manager) and redux library.
- Interacted with the Testing Team, Scrum Masters and Business Analysts to fix issues.

EDUCATION

University of Helsinki, Finland

May 2011- Sep 2015

- Bachelor of Science (BS).
- Get Third place at ACM, part of International College Programming Contest(ICPC)

PROJECTS

- https://www.getflair.io
- https://perfectyourtrading.com
- https://www.fazwaz.com
- https://nftcars.me

- https://cropper.finance
- https://shmacked.com
- https://www.bobbytariq.com